



Personal Information

MOBILE: +598 99 270 789

EMAIL: alex.devsysop@gmail.com

LINKEDIN: https://www.linkedin.com/in/alxsenen/

SUMMARY

I am a person passionate about technology with 10 years of experience, managing systems and services in Linux and Windows, also quickly troubleshooting and writing a step plan. I am empathetic, proactive, fast learner, serious and responsible. I have been working with many teams, improving my skills, implementing providing best practices and solutions. I will always give my best for the teams and the clients.

Work experience

02/2022-12/2022 | Devops Engineer, Soho, Uruguay

Working with clusters on EKS.

CI/CD automation and integrations with pipelines using tools like Azure Devops.

Deploy infrastructure using Terraform on AWS.

12/2021-02/2022 Devops Engineer, Inswitch, Uruguay

Working with clusters on K8s, OKD, EKS and VMware.

CI/CD integrations with pipelines using tools like Jenkins and Gitlab.

Automation deployments to minimize delays for implementations.

11/2019-12/2021 | SysOps & Cloud Services, SONDA, Uruguay

Deploying servers on AWS, GCP, Azure, VMware, using many systems like CentOS, RedHat, openSUSE, Debian,

Ubuntu.

Starting with basic Docker and Kubernetes, deploying services for internal infrastructure and external clients.

 $Deploying \ and \ controlling \ systems \ integration \ with \ Jenkins \ and \ Ansible \ using \ our \ own \ GitLab \ internal \ repository.$

09/2018-09/2019 | Sysadmin, IT Support Engineer, Webmaster, Etecsa, Cuba

Working with Linux and Windows environments as server or desktop client.

Doing support to many web-platforms and servers used by different teams.

Automation of installations servers using Ansible's playbooks.

Managing domain servers with Zentyal and applying network policies.

Implementing firewalls, dns servers, and others services like ftp, webservers, mail servers (Zimbra).

06/2014-09/2018 | Sysadmin, IT Support Engineer, Webmaster, DATYS, Cuba

Mantaining linux and windows servers on (Windows Server 2003-2011), (Debian, Ubuntu).

Design, deploy of internal and external websites use it by team using drupal framework.

Working side by side with research teams looking for best solutions and how to improve systems for tests runner.

09/2010-06/2014 | Sysadmin, IT Technical Security, Webmaster, UCI, Cuba

Webmaster of Information Security website, helping and teaching users how to confront cyber attacks avoiding pishing, malwares, etc.

Running servers for scanning lan networks, searching for virus, malwares, keyloggers, storing all data in a phosocal server on datacenter.

Mantaining linux and windows servers on (Windows Server 2003), (CentOS, Redhat).

SKILLS

1. VMware, AWS, GCP, Azure 2. CentOS, RedHat, openSUSE, Debian, Ubuntu, Windows Servers 3. Jenkins, Gitlab, Ansible, Bash 4. Apache, Nginx, JBoss, Wildfly 5. Jira, Confluence, Bitbucket 6. MySQL, PostgreSQL 7. DevOps Jr. Docker, Kubernetes, Pipelines 8. Troubleshooting

EDUCATION

2017 - 2019	Telecommunications and Electronics Engineering, ISPJAE - Incompleted
2017 - 2018	Linux Services Administrator, DATYS - Completed
08/2011	Linux System Administrator II, UCI - Completed
07/2010	Linux System Administrator I, UCI - Completed
2004 - 2008	Bachelor of Electronic (B.Elect.), PITOH - Completed

Languages

- English Intermediate
- Spanish Native